DAMIAN C. ROSSNEY

WEB DEVELOPER

damian@rossney.net rossney.net

.....

(914) 227-4202

linkedin.com/in/damianrossney

dcr8898

Skills

OVERVIEW

Excellent written and oral communication skills

Outstanding research skills

High technical proficiencies

Highly motivated and disciplined

Organized and detail oriented

Resourceful and hard working

Able to work independently or in collaboration

Adept at performing multiple complex tasks simultaneously

TECHNICAL

Languages:

Ruby, JavaScript

Frameworks:

Rails, Sinatra, jQuery, Handlebars

Databases:

PostrgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite

Front End:

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Skeleton

Testing:

Heroku

Rspec, Jasmine, Capybara, SimpleCov

Version Control: Git, GitHub, BitBucket

Continuous Deployment:

Continuous Integration: CircleCl

Methodologies:
Agile, Kanban, TDD,
OOD/OOP, MVC, REST, AJAX

OTHER

Experienced instructor (legal research and computer skills)

Summary

I am a full stack developer with prior experience as a paralegal. I enjoy solving complex problems and building practical things. When I realized that the most interesting task I completed as a paralegal was parsing a huge FDA database with raw SQL to extract adverse incident data on a particular robotic surgery device, I knew it was time for a change. On my new path, I have developed projects using Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, JavaScript (native, jQuery, Handlebars, etc.), SQL (PostgreSQL, MySQL, and SQLite), ORMs (primarily Active Record), HTML5, and CSS3. I have utilized Test-Driven Development using Rspec, Jasmine, and Capybara, and followed Agile methodologies such as Kanban. I am currently expanding my repertoire to include additional web languages, such as PHP and Python.

Projects

There's A Board (Core Developer) (https://github/theresaboard)

- Ruby/Rails for backend and API.
- JavaScript for custom front end (utilizing AJAX for API consumption).
- jQuery, FullCalendar, Bootstrap, for front end presentation and calendar interaction.
- Test Driven Development using Rspec.
- CircleCI and SimpleCov for continuous integration and coverage analysis.
- OmniAuth/Auth0 for OAuth integration.
- GitHub for version control.
- Heroku for continuous deployment.

Experience

Wilson Elser Moskowitz Edelman & Dicker, LLP Senior Paralegal

White Plains, NY Mar 2010 to May 2015

Managed complex litigation from inception through trial, settlement, and appeals, including:

- Legal Research: Dispositive motions, procedural issues, and appeals.
- Investigative Research: Background research on parties and expert witnesses, medical research for both causation and liability.
- Electronic Discovery: Forensic collection and preservation of electronic data, and processing and evaluation of data produced by adversarial parties
- Discovery Tracking: Custom database development to track, organize, and analyze documents by their contents and associated metadata.
- Trial Technology: Assisted in the presentation of evidence, including electronic evidence and expert
 material; coordinated and developed trial technology, including trial infrastructure (networks, etc.),
 presentation technology, and evidence preparation.
- Exhibit Creation: Demonstrative exhibits for trials, including both video and illustrations; also collaborated with experts witnesses to coordinate and prepare expert exhibits and presentations.
- Legal presentations: For example, researched and created presentation on the medical record privacy
 implications of the Health Insurance Portability and Privacy Act, delivered to prospective client hospitals and
 nursing homes.

Bartlett McDonough Bastone & Monaghan, LLP

White Plains, NY Jan 2005 to Mar 2010

Litigation Paralegal

Supported attorneys through all phases of litigation and appeals in a mid-sized defense-litigation firm. Primarily medical malpractice defense, some premises liability and product liability defense, a small number of labor matters and plaintiff personal injury cases.

Paralegal & Research Assistant Independent

New York 1999 to 2005

Directly assisted clients appearing before state and federal administrative agencies. Conducted research, drafted correspondence, memoranda, and appellate briefs. Assisted attorneys on a case-by-case basis in all phases of administrative proceedings and civil and criminal litigation.

Education

Dev Bootcamp Graduate 2015

Skidmore College UWW B.S. Business Administration (Minor in Math) 1998